Blanca MANCILLA

4265, rue Jean-Brillant Montréal (Québec) H3T 1P2, Canada +1.514.591.2007

Email: blancalmancilla@gmail.com
Blog: superspreadsheet.wordpress.com

github handle: bluciam

Written, spoken: English, French, Spanish.

Other: German, B1 level, currently in Goethe Institut.

In LinkedIn

Professional Profile

I have +10 years of experience in IT and over a year in Web development. I want to use my skills in coding, problem solving, design, writing, documentation, formalization, leadership, lectureship and inter-communication in a development team. I am always learning new things, experimenting the latest technologies or on Twitter.

Computer skills snapshot

Web programming in Ruby on Rails, testing, CSS and Bootstrap, HTML. Open source development tools, Linux, scripting languages, git, github, bitbucket, LTEX. Teaching knowledge in C, C++, JSP, java, haskell, geographical information systems, human computer interaction, information systems, computer graphics.

Current

2012-present Consultant, Montreal, Canada

- · Web developer:
 - From design to deployment as sole developer in Ruby on Rails for a Montreal startup (on going).
 - Front-end development including own design using CSS and HTML:
 http://vinka-creations.bitballoon.com.
- · Technical writer: rewrite developers' interviews as reports and proposals.

Research Software

 $\textbf{SuperSpreadSheet} \ (S^3) \text{, https://github.com/bluciam/superspreadsheet}$

The purpose of this project was to demonstrate the use of contextual electronic documents: case study, the multi-spreadsheet. It covered conception, research, design and implementation.

Anita Conti Mapping Server, https://github.com/bluciam/anita-jsp-2005

The ACMS project was developed as a proof of concept. Development iterations had to accommodate the constant change of requirements, tools and research discoveries. It was successful in its purpose.

TransLucid Project, http://sourceforge.net/projects/translucid/

As a team member, I was part of the design and planning stages of creating the TransLucid language. I devised the documentation structure and tailored it to different audiences. As the first user, I was the main interactive tester of the system.

Education

1999-2004	PhD, Computer Science, UNSW, Sydney, Australia
1993-1995	MSc, Geomatic Sciences, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1992-1993	French as a second language, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1990	Seminar on Research, Summer Program, SUNY at Stony Brook, USA
1989-1991	BSc, Computer Electronic Science, Iona College, NY, USA
1984–1988	BEng, Computer Systems Engineering (four of five years), Universidad Industrial de Santander (UIS), Colombia

Past Positions

- 2004–2016 Faculty Member, University of New South Wales (UNSW), Australia
 - · Theses supervisor, assessor, adviser; lecturer in Computer Science.
 - · Researcher, team member, documentation writer, software evaluator.
 - · Assignment conception, specification, deployment and marking.
- 2009–2012 Faculty Member, University of Technology, Sydney (UTS), Australia
 - · Lecturer, curriculum redesigner and specification writer.
- 1993–1995 **Student Assistant** in Remote Sensing, Laval University, Québec, Canada
 - · Group tutor, software lab instructure, marker.
- 1991–1992 **System Administrator** of IBM AS/400, Electro-Alloys, NY, USA

Conference and Workshops Organization

2001-2002	International Conference on Distributed Communities on the Web, DCW 2002
	Local Arrangements Chair: Webmaster; budget and conference manager.
2000-2002	Women in Computing, UNSW, Director:
	Liaison between community stakeholders; conception of events.
2000-2003	Girls in Science and Technology Workshops, UNSW, Founder organizer:
	Workshops on HTML, lego mindstorms and iMovie; host.

Publications, http://plaice.web.cse.unsw.edu.au/~plaice/archive/BLM

Total	28	Books	1	Book Chapters	1
		Journal Articles	5	Theses	2
		Conference Articles	17	Compilations	2